Welcome everyone to our fourth day of
the Kaggle Generative AI Intensive
course, which is all about
domain-specific large language models
and how you can fine-tune and customize
large language models to be exactly
right for your use cases. Um, my name is
Paige and I'm really excited to be here
today to get to introduce you to all of
our expert question answers and also to
have a walk-through through all of our
code labs and our code labs for
Generative AI Intensive courses. Um,
just as a reminder for our course
overview, um, this is a five-day
Generative AI Intensive course with
Google, um, sponsored by Kaggle and the
Gemini team. We are on day number four
and this course includes a collection of
daily assignments, so some podcasts and
some white papers that I hope you had a
chance to walk through, um, some Discord
discussion, so a place where you can ask
questions, get them answered, and also
perhaps even have them answered by, uh,
one of our expert hosts live as one of
our, uh, as one of our daily videos, um,
and also a lot of additional resources
for you to go to look at at to learn
more. Um, today, as I mentioned, we're
going to be learning all about
fine-tuning, um, domain-specific LLMs,
um, so being able to take a new data
set, uh,
uh, use it, uh, with something like
Laura fine-tuning or or a different
approach to to make a large language
model especially effective for your use
case, um, uh, and we'll be walking
through some code labs, uh, in a few
short moments, um, that demonstrate how
to do this. Um, so tomorrow we'll be
going into ML Ops for Generative AI, but
today we're going to be learning all
about Sec-ML, Med-Palm, uh, and have
some insights from the very researchers
who built them. Um, so with that, I am
going to go ahead and introduce, um,
Anant, uh, who will be walking through
the curriculum review and also our code
labs, um, with a special thank you to
Mark McDonald who helped, uh, uh helped
build them and create the content. Um
so, Anant, do you want to go ahead and
share your screen and start walking
folks through the walking folks through
the code?
Yeah. Um but before we do that, Paige,
uh wanted to uh welcome everyone and uh
and before we start off on the codelab,
I wanted to quickly give you a recap of
what we're going to be covering today.
Um uh the codelab, the the white paper
behind it, as well as the uh a quick
recap of the previous days and how it
all fits together. So, uh as you might
have if you've been following through
day one, day one we covered foundational
models, how they're built, trained,
their applications, etc. And on day two,
we looked at embeddings and how you can
represent complex uh objects uh in a in
a compact semantic uh space and how they
can be queried and managed at scale. And
yesterday in day three, we looked at how
both of them come together to make uh to
can be come together to make dynamic
agents, which allow um LLMs to be used
for applications where they need to
dynamically refer to different sources,
use tools, and function calling in order
to achieve tasks which are not directly
achievable through LLMs alone.
And now in today, um you might might
have read the uh white paper on uh on um
the center around on domain-specific
models, specifically in the security and
healthcare domain. And uh this uh uh and
they kind of combined the concepts we
had learned in the previous days, and
that's what uh we that we're diving into
today and the codelabs will be about.
So, um we began the white paper uh by
exploring the challenges facing
healthcare. Now, I'm by imagining the
complexity of um uh
of diagnosing a patient accurately,
where you need to consider all of their
symptoms, medical history, and test
results. This requires often a deep
understanding of uh not only medical
concepts, but often also the ability to
retrieve relevant uh information and
reasoning skills to arrive at the
correct conclusion, right? So, we then
discussed how Med-PaLM tackles this,
highlighting its journey through passing
the US medical licensing exam to its
potential for real-world clinical
impact, such as assisting doctors
with various tasks, such as diagnosis
and treatment planning. We also touched
upon the crucial need for long-form
answers, understanding medical records,
and engaging in basically what we
consider natural dialogues with
patients, not just robotic mechanical
ones.
Then, in the white paper, we shifted
gears to cybersecurity, where
we we explored how practitioners are
constantly battling the what we call the
three Ts: threats, toil, and talent. So,
to elaborate further, imagine a security
analyst just sifting through mountains
of alerts trying to identify real
attacks from harmless anomalies. This is
essentially the reality behind toil in
cybersecurity, and if you add to that
the constant evolution of cyber threats
and global shortage of skilled
professionals, you have basically a
recipe for burnout and vulnerability.
So, in this part of the white paper, we
delve into how Sec-PaLM helps by
analyzing malicious code, automating
alert triage, and even generating
reports,
freeing up human analysts to focus on
more strategic and important tasks that
they would be required for.
And we also explored in this white paper
the unique features of both Med-PaLM and
Sec-PaLM that make them so effective, as
as well as Med-PaLM.
We we discussed we discussed also that
how these specialized language models
are trained on vast amounts of medical
and cybersecurity data, enabling them to
understand the nuances of their domains.
We also examined how they leverage
planning and reasoning frameworks to
break down complex tasks into small
manageable steps, much like how we as
humans would uh human experts would.
And towards the end, we touched upon
responsible deployment of these powerful
AI models in real-world settings and
emphasized the importance of how
evaluation
and basically to address potential
biases and also ensuring that they are
used safely and ethically to
improve patient care and strengthen
cybersecurity defenses. So,
hopefully that give you a good overview
of the content that we covered in this
in this white paper and let us now jump
into the collabs and see how it how it
all
fits together in in the wider scheme of
things.
So, give me 1 second.
Okay.
Hope everybody can see my screen.
So, the first collab
uh
uh was around um
Sorry. Uh
collab, but yeah. So, it was around
Google search grounding and this collab
basically talks about um
how
how you can use grounding techniques
such as Google search grounding to to
improve improve the the
accuracy and reduce hallucinations for
large language models. In the SEC-ML
side of things, grounding is used as
well. So, you'll hear more about that or
read it in the white paper later.
So, in this part of the collab, we just
like every other collab that we have
gone through before, we start off by
initializing the
the
the Well, sorry. This part of the collab
first start off by seeing how the AI
studio side of things work. So, if you
use a if you uh um if you use the UI in
AI studio, you can also try out
grounding there through the user
interface. Um but we'll be focusing more
on the API side of things. So, just like
every other collab, we are initializing
well, uh installing the respective
libraries, retrieving the Google AI
studio um API key through Kaggle
secrets, importing the necessary
libraries as well.
And then comes the interesting parts.
So, first we explore the various models
available to us um because for this
collab um um we are we'll be using the
standard models that we have in the
previous days.
Uh however, we'll be augmenting them
with grounding. So, specifically Google
search grounding where the uh through
the uh interface where through the SDK
interface, we'll be um
augme- uh we'll be grounding the
responses on Google search, hence
improving and improving the not only the
quality, but also be getting sources and
citations from Google search to kind of
understand which parts of the answer can
be attributed to which um search
results.
So,
uh
if you've tried it out, you'll see that
uh um
like Taylor Swift, like if you ask when
and where is the Taylor Swift's next
concert, this is often something that
requires dynamic and real-time
information. Um in day two, we looked at
how uh RAG can help provide this. So,
providing dynamic and real-time
information um is something because LLMs
are trained at a certain point in time
and they might not have the latest
information. So, then if you ask the
model, it uh it can give you a response
either an incorrect response or mention
that it doesn't have real-time
information and point you to various
sources. However, that is not the answer
probably that you were looking for. So,
moving on in the part after that, we
enable uh we give it a tool like tools
which was discussed yesterday in the
agents chapter, you might remember that.
We are giving it a tool called Google
search retrieval and then repeating the
same question, and you would see then it
manages to come up with a specific, more
accurate answer.
And but having the answer um is good,
but how would you know you can trust the
answer based on actual sources? And
that's where you can dive deeper into
the metadata provided by
um provided by um
this um this service, and you can see
that gives you various links and results
based on the query you ask, um as well
as um you can also get in not only the
links which are used to generate the
answer, the sources, but you can also
see which parts, I mean depending on
which question you ask, uh which parts
was uh uh were used for generating the
sources uh for generating the sources um
and
which part of the answer you can
attribute it to as well.
So, this is what essentially this Colab
is primarily about, about generating
grounded text and getting citations for
certain segments of the uh output
answers. So,
uh and this is essentially uh what
majorly this Colab covers. Now, that was
um
uh static grounding, where we kind of we
kind of asked the model to ground every
answer in Google search results, but
there might be scenarios where you you
want to strategically ground the results
based on uh if it requires grounding or
not. So, the answers to the model is
unable to answer properly or
appropriately based on but without
grounding, you probably don't want to
defer to grounding for. And this is
where um
uh like you can kind of supply the model
with a threshold, and the model then
automatically manages to um
uh
uh uh like uh redirect to the grounding
service or not based on how confident it
is in its answer.
So, that is essentially what this part
of the Colab is about. So, using
grounding to um
uh to improve the reduce hallucinations
and improve the quality of your results.
If you the second and part of things in
the white paper
use grounding and you can utilize it in
your applications as well.
Give me um
So moving on to the other
uh collab which talks about fine-tuning
a custom model and this part of the
collab talks about
um
uh fine-tuning a custom model
and it does so by
by
using parameter efficient fine-tuning
techniques like what you learned on the
first day where you can fine-tune the
Gemini model on your own corpus and it
can help it perform better on unseen
tasks.
Um so we start off by initializing the
API key as usual
importing it through the Kaggle secrets
exporting exploring the various
available models.
And now just like we we saw on day two
we'll be using the same newsgroups text
data set which contains over 18,000
um
newsgroups posts on 20 topics and we'll
be we'll be
we'll be classifying the newsgroups
posts into various categories so it's
essentially a classification problem
based on their on their text. So just
like the second day we'll be preparing
the data set we'll be cleaning
cleaning the data set to remove any
obvious signals of the category the the
news post news post belongs to to make
it relevant fairly.
And yeah that's the same as the day two
data set and then we'll be sampling
certain rows
for training and also for for testing.
Remember
parameter efficient fine-tuning
is is very data efficient So, you do not
need as many rows as you did for the
embedding model. It's even more data
efficient. So, we only keep 50 rows for
training. That's also one of the things
you'd like to highlight here. And then
we
um
uh keep some for testing as well.
Now, in order to understand how
fine-tuning can help improve
performance, it's good to have a
baseline to see how the model would
behave or what the classification
performance would be with zero-shot
classification before fine-tuning. So,
this is what we do in this part of the
Colab where we
we have the model
um
uh do zero-shot classification by asking
it from which newsgroup does the
following message originate. And I give
it a few options. And uh and we do a bit
more prompt engineering here to make it
more like specific.
Uh and but however, either way, as you
can see here and we the accuracy is only
around
in 18.75%.
That is without parameter efficient
fine-tuning. Now, if you repeat the same
process, but after tuning, if you repeat
the same evaluation process, but after
fine-tuning uh
the model on input-output pairs
examples, there's 50 examples we took
which contain like newsgroup posts and
their respective categories, you can see
that the
um the evaluation
uh evaluation of the model uh improves
uh
evaluation
classification performance of the model
improves significantly to uh and this
can be um
a major advantage, especially in
scenarios where your tasks are not
exactly
uh something the model has seen before.
Now, you can of course improve
performance with prompt engineering as
well, as you've seen in the first day.
So, I would I would recommend play
around uh and you can see that later.
Now, moving ahead, um there's another
advantage to parameter-efficient
fine-tuning, which is not often cited,
which you'll also see in this part of
the Colab, which is that it can be used
to reduce the amount of tokens
generated. And especially since
when you use the paid version of these
APIs, you're charged on both the length
of the input as well as the generated
output.
It tends to reduce the length of the
length of both sides, especially because
you can influence the output quite a
output length quite a lot. And because
we trained our parameter-efficient
trained the model on
to be very
let's say size-efficient
in in in its input from
by mapping from its input to output,
because we do not need additional prompt
engineering on the input side, we can
see that we saved we
Yeah, we saved quite a lot on the token
because the inputs were shorter and
hence you spend
less on the input side. So, yeah, that
would be all. Please take away my screen
share page.
Um
page. Oh, yes. I I think the I think
you're you have to stop sharing your
screen, Anant. I I unfortunately I can't
I can't take it away for you. Um
Okay. Yep, there we go. Excellent. Good
job. I I loved the I loved the Colabs. I
especially love this new search
grounding feature. I think it's going to
be really helpful for everyone who wants
to incorporate kind of more grounded,
up-to-date, current information
with Gemini.
And it's as easy as just making one
modification, like one-line change in a
function. So, so this is very very cool
to see.
I think people can test it out today in
AI Studio. Um which is which is great.
And then also via APIs, though I do
believe there might be a paid tier
associated with the APIs. Um so, that is
fantastic. Thank you so much. All right,
and now it's time for our Q&A with our
expert hosts from the Med-PaLM and
Sec-PaLM teams. I'm really excited to
have everyone here today to talk a
little bit about how they've been using
fine-tuned LLMs specifically for their
customers and for their use cases. Um
but before we get into the Q&A, I want
to give a special shout-out to all of
our generative AI course moderators um
to Polon, Cause, Mark, Eric, Irwin,
Miles, and Guillaume, who have been
tirelessly answering questions in the
Discord chat, um as well as answering
questions on YouTube and on Kaggle, um
specifically related to the course
content. Uh the sun never really sleeps
on the Gemini and generative AI teams at
Google, and I'm sure y'all have
experienced that as you've been asking
questions on Discord. So, thanks so
much. Virtual round of applause um to
all of our expert uh our expert
moderators. And uh and now we're going
to get into uh our day four um our day
four guests um for Scott, Christopher,
Umesh, and Antonio, um
uh folks from uh places as varied at
Google as health AI um with the Med-PaLM
work, as well as uh Sec-PaLM doing AI as
applied to security domains, um and then
also our Office of the Cloud CTO. So,
really excited to have everyone here
today, um and thank you so much for
taking the time to come in and to talk
to all of our generative AI intensive
course learners um about what you've
been working on. Um I'm going to start
with our first question, which is for
Umesh and for Scott. Um tell me a little
bit about large language models for
security. Um what are they, and why are
they useful?
Yeah, great. Um happy to be here. Um
just a quick little bit of background
for me. I I run the uh data science
research team in Google Cloud Security
that uh builds Sec-PaLM. Um and I've
actually been working in this space of
ML applied to security here for going on
20 22 years now. So, I've seen quite the
progression. LLMs is definitely like an
interesting new area for us. Um, so this
question is like very much pertinent and
very top of mind for for the entire
field, honestly. Um, and so, you know, I
think probably the way to start is to
think about, well, like what makes
cybersecurity a little bit different
than some of the other sort of typical
business areas where an LLM will be
applied.
Um, I think the first thing to note is
that in cybersecurity, it's not one big
monolithic thing. There's actually tons
of different tasks that people, um, you
know, perform on a day-to-day basis to
do cybersecurity work. Everything from
doing binary code analysis and malware
analysis to triaging alerts to, uh, you
know, doing more devops style
administration of your of your network.
And so,
um, you know, the the the tools, the
data that's being used, the sheer
diversity of different tools and data,
um, you know, really make this kind of
interesting in that you don't really get
this like overwhelming momentum of data
public data available, right? Um, as you
would in a lot of other cases for LLMs.
Um, another kind of confounding factor
here is that a lot of that data is
typically considered to be highly
sensitive by organizations, right?
Security is normally people's, you know,
right next to health and PII is is, you
know, pretty much right there right
there on the list of things that they
don't want to have revealed uh,
publicly. Uh, which again further
reduces the the potential for, you know,
what's available publicly for us. Um,
and then the last thing is that, you
know, if you think about a lot of the
tasks that threat researchers and and
malware analysts do, they oftentimes
border like right on the edge of what
you might call safety mechanisms for in
the more general sense, right? So, if
you're doing malware analysis or you're,
you know, trying to cut that, you know,
develop a plan for red teaming your
network, those seem an awful lot like
things that would trigger a safety
mechanism, and they often do. And so,
the combination of all these things
taken together means that, you know,
it's really hard for a generalist model
to really have an expert level of
understanding and reasoning about all of
this variety of data such that it really
covers all these customer needs that
that you might have.
Um so, that kind of is the motivation
behind it. You know, you know, what it
is specifically, you can kind of think
about starting at one of these
foundational models. Um but, we have a
continued pre-training task where we
kind of feed it more special,
specialized expert-level books and uh
documents about cybersecurity to just
kind of build its vocabulary in that
space. Um and then we have a bunch of
very specific um fine-tuning tasks. So,
we do full parameter fine-tuning, um
but, these instruction tuning type of
tasks are very much pointed at these
areas where the generalist model is
unlikely to have seen or be exposed to
things, right? So, like, for instance,
analyzing very long-form security
alerts, right? And really truly
understanding uh you know, not just from
inferring what the the keys and values
are, but actually truly understanding
what's happening in the alert.
Um once that's done, we have an all the
human alignment process, which again is
a really interesting thought because
when you're you have such a diverse uh
area as cybersecurity, there's lots of
different humans with lots of different
interests in in what they want the model
to actually be providing it to them. So,
like, a threat analyst might be
different than a security uh operations
analyst.
Um and then finally, we we often
leverage uh fine-tuning
as Ananth had mentioned, uh you know, we
use Laura-based fine-tuning to do um
basically specialization towards either
specific customer environments or, you
know, tasks that maybe are particularly
out of distribution for the the core
models and kind of need a little more
extra reinforcement somehow. Um
you know, I think they're particularly
useful because frankly, even though the
generalist models might be able to get
you there, you know, they might be able
to provide an answer in a lot of cases,
um the rate of hallucination for those
answers tends to be higher than if you
were just to use a specialized model.
And in some cases, it just simply cannot
actually perform the tasks at all in any
sort of reasonable way. Like you know, a
number of specialized domain specific
languages, uh query languages that, you
know, it's very very important to pull
new data using and unfortunately,
because they're poorly represented in
sort of the public internet, the models
simply don't really know what to do,
right? Like often times, it'll just spit
out SQL, but you can't use SQL in these
instances. You have to have the the
specialized language. So, um that's I
think
sort of the the what and the why of
using it. Um I will say here though that
one last bit is that
you know, I think a lot of people think
of LLMs as like memorization machines.
Like let's pack as much information into
it as we can. And that's actually the
opposite of what our thought process is.
We actually are very much focused on it
performing tasks on data rather than it
memorizing something. And the reason for
that is, you know, as Anat mentioned in
in his intro was, you know, threats
evolve on a daily basis. So, you could
easily imagine how this is going to
totally blow up in our face if we try to
like give it the the most latest
information on threats every single day.
We'll be basically retraining an LLM
every 24 hours in order to try to make
it relevant, and that's clearly not a
viable option.
That's wonderful. I love that you call
out how the pre-training data, kind of
the the information that the base models
are trained on is really, really
sort of
security use cases are underrepresented,
which means that the model as part of
its pre-training process never learns
how to do those kinds of tasks. Or if it
does learn, it might learn only kind of
the most
sort of remedial 100 101 level
steps as opposed to the to the more
detailed like enterprise grade security
kind of challenges that y'all are trying
to tackle. Yeah. Or or only the most
important, you know, the most well-used
or popular tools that are out there and
then ignoring the very long tail of
things that people have in their
environment.
Excellent. So So next for the next
question,
let's go to let's take
sort of turn to the healthcare space.
Chris, how are you thinking about
benchmarks like Med-QA and when will we
reach 100% on Med-QA?
Thanks, Paige. Hi, I'm Chris. I'm
working in Google research on health AI.
And for as you've seen in the white
papers, basically a couple of years ago,
we published our first medical model
Med-PaLM, which was the first model to
achieve a passing mark on Med-QA. And
Med-QA, just for context, is basically a
multiple choice test that is similar to
questions taken by medical students for
the license exam.
It is a few sentences describing a
scenario, a patient with a couple of lab
values or a couple of symptoms and so
on. And then three to five options on
what the right answer is.
And then just
many hundred questions of those and then
you get a benchmark overall.
And the big upside of the benchmark is
that this was attempted for many
decades. So we have a good comparison
across many technology evolutions on how
good or not good technology was able to
get there, like 10% correct, 20%
correct, and so on.
And
if you look forward to uh a year two
ago, it reached a passing bar, it
reached the expert level bar. And if you
look like today, a couple of models, uh
including Gemini for instance, are
achieving the 90% range of answers.
The big downside is it's a little bit of
an artificial scenario.
Like the patient information is very
compressed, um while for instance in
reality, a patient information is like a
full health record of many years and
medical images and lab values and so on.
And secondly, it's multiple choice,
which is easy to compare, so it's very
good to evaluate automatically, but it's
not very realistic. Like most doctors
don't have mul- multiple choice
available when they look at a real case.
So,
are we going to reach 100% on benchmarks
like MedQA?
Probably. Somebody's going to get there.
Um
I would attach some questions of whether
it memorized how to answer test
questions whether how to really reason
understand medical knowledge.
But what I really anticipate is going to
happen more and more
is that we're moving on
once a benchmark reached the 90% bar,
that we're moving on to more
sophisticated or benchmarks or
benchmarks that are much closer to
reality. So, for instance, if you look
at the papers of the last year from our
group, you saw like many more medical
imaging tasks or you saw like hard case
challenges where you see a full patient
scenario and you need to come up with a
diagnosis or treatment recommendation
for the sake of understanding whether
the models could do those kind of tasks.
Um so, that's my real hope that we're
moving on to more and more complex
benchmarks and sophisticated benchmarks.
Um
and I assume MedQA, yeah, somebody will
reach 100%, but I don't see
uh that as a very important milestone
anymore as such.
Yeah. I love that you call out that we
need better benchmarks, especially for
these highly highly specialized expert
tasks.
Um because to your point, the uh
multiple-choice questions it would be
beautiful if life was as simple as a
multiple-choice question
uh answering test, but uh it would uh
and fortunately, you know, the world is
a little bit more complex for that. So,
so I hope folks listening today are
inspired to create better medical
benchmarks for large language models. Um
especially uh especially things that are
a bit more complex than than
multiple-choice Q&A.
Awesome.
So, next question. This is for Antonio.
Um welcome. Uh Antonio is one of the the
leads in our Google Cloud Office of the
CTO.
Um Antonio, what are the tradeoffs that
you've seen between general-purpose and
fine-tuned models? Um or is it that uh
fine-tuned models are eventually just
going to have all of their knowledge
baked into the base models themselves?
Well, thanks for the question. Well,
perhaps first I introduce myself. Uh I
work for Office of the CTO, an
organization in Cloud.
Um and uh all my life I was working in
AI. Before uh before working in Cloud, I
was working in Search.
I went to
to to check when was my first paper in
Search was 27 years ago. So, long, long
time ago.
Uh a lot of changes in AI in in this uh
in this period. Well, in the last uh 3-4
years, I would say that we saw uh a
number of
models always increasing in size.
And today the situation is that we have
models that are very large and able to
deal with complex
uh queries,
very complex prompts. For instance,
Gemini Pro is such a model. And we have
models that that are
efficient.
Uh still able to deal with a
complex queries, but more efficient from
the point of view of latency, from the
point of view of cost.
And so, there is a need to balance and
take pre- trade-offs in in in these
models.
And people are normally looking at uh
you know, when they trade make these
trade-offs, they look at different
dimensions.
Including, for instance, the quality of
the answer, the cost of serving the
answer, the speed I mean, the latency.
And there is a a need to very frequently
to simultaneously optimize this uh
this uh multiple dimensions. So, the
reason why there is an interest in
specific domain models is because uh you
can actually uh have some some good
gains with models that are smaller, but
specialized in in particular in
particular domains.
And so, for instance, uh
uh security and medicine are two
examples, but there are many other
examples.
The good news is that today uh there are
a a broad range of tools that we can use
to do to do this.
Um you can start with fine-tuning. There
were discussions about fine-tuning
earlier and today and also in the
previous days.
Where you essentially take a model that
is already trained and you adapt this
model to a specific domain, providing
some example in the specific domain.
This is uh if you think about this, this
is a form of semi-static adaptation. You
were mentioning before
that, you know, fine-tuning is happening
at a specific moment in time. So, it's a
snapshot of what the situation up to
that particular point.
Sometimes this works really very well.
There are situations where you want to
have more dynamic information.
And so, perhaps have some information is
provided in context
uh when you
do inference or when you submit the
prompt. And there techniques like
retrieval augmentation or based on
search can help a lot.
Or also, you know, in context learning
where you provide this
additional information or
uh at prompt time, perhaps using
techniques like caching to improve the
efficiency, reduce the cost.
I would say that there is a
There are multiple options to optimize.
It really depends on the specific use
case.
But I see a balance between this
happening more this different dimensions
happening more and more.
Awesome. Thank you. Thank you for the
great answer. I I agree that the
I'm just going to reshare my slide deck
really quick. I agree that the
the fine-tuning for fine-tuning for
large language models can get
significant gains that maybe you not
maybe you might not be able to get just
by using the base model. So so lots of
options for for fine-tuning both offered
through Google Cloud as well as open
source frameworks like Unsloth.
So so hopefully
hopefully that that will get addressed.
Next question kind of related
for for Christopher to answer
is will a single superior model solve
all health problems? This seems like an
ambitious goal even for even for large
language models and for generative AI.
Yeah, all health problems is a very
broad scope. Um what I
the way I like to think about it is to
take a little bit of a perspective
before GenAI. So if you just zoom out
over the last couple of hundred years,
um clinical studies did not exist a
couple of hundred years ago.
Vaccines did not exist a couple of
hundred years ago. Um
uh
uh regular visits for for um
for preemptive care did not exist a
couple of hundred years ago. So, many
things that we are using nowadays in
modern health care did not exist in the
past and had to be invented.
And when I hear about people thinking
about using genuine health care, I hear
good chunk of use cases where they
basically try to make something more
efficient or make something better. Like
use this and this to help the doctor
write a reply to the patient faster.
Um use this and that for the patient to
help them educate themselves better.
Um use this for medical imaging tasks
and so on.
And those are all good, and I think it
will improve things. But what I'm
waiting for is both scientific
discoveries, but also the different
pathways of care that are possible now
that would not have been possible before
models like Gemini or Med Gemini or
Med-PaLM.
So, this is really the the big step in
health care that I anticipate to happen
in the next 10 years. Um where I'm
really hoping for a lot of innovations
and and inventions to come along.
Um will health care be solved at that
time? Uh
no, that's a
journey for lifetime. Uh but it will get
closer. Um
so, but my short message is incremental
improvements and efficiency improvements
are important, but they are not the only
thing we can do. And thinking different
as in what is possible now that was
impossible to think about in the past,
those are the things we need to explore
more.
I love it, and that's very inspiring. It
also seems to It seems to hint that
we're just at the beginning of this
journey and that we still have a lot of
untapped opportunity for people to apply
AI in the health care domain, um as well
as to many other specialized domains.
So so really really excited to see what
the next few years hold.
Next question.
Another one for security.
It's inherently an adversarial field.
Does the adversarial nature change your
strategies for where and how you deploy
large language models
for security purposes and how is this
changed over time?
You know, you you mentioned I believe
Scott that you had started doing this a
couple of decades ago.
How has the sort of perspective on where
large language models do their inference
changed over time?
Yeah, that's that's a good question.
Yeah, I'll give my share chance to
respond as well, but you know, I think
the the big thing is that you know, a
couple decades ago no one even saw the
adversarial you know, sort of
vulnerability that ML could provide,
right? I think
I guess now it's like 15 12 years ago
something like that. Some of the first
evasion papers came out and people
realized that oh wow, this is actually
possible to just get around all of this
ML that we're using and I think it you
know, first to some degree the LLMs are
an extension of that, right? It's a it's
a new
new attack surface so to speak that we
now have to continue monitoring and and
kind of look out for how we incorporate
into our tool chain.
Yeah, I'll add to what Scott said.
If you build any kind of application,
you have to think about security.
And whatever you take dependencies on
external sources of things, then you
need to consider you know, what where's
that coming from? What's the likelihood
that it could be compromised or
malicious?
And that includes things like if you
include open source libraries in your
code,
right?
It includes if you're taking
input from a user that might be trying
to do something bad to your system, you
have to sanitize the input and use it
carefully and correctly.
All those same principles still apply
in this world. It's just that there's
new and different ways that people are
going to exploit them. So, for example,
you know, maybe it's not the
open-source, well, it might also be the
open-source code that you're using,
uh but the data that goes into training
a model very often is sourced from
external places, right? Because you
can't generate enough just
in yourself to get the results that you
want.
And so, you have to be very careful
about, you know, cleaning that data,
ensuring its accuracy, ensuring it meets
your safety standards, and so forth.
Uh the runtime part also exists, right?
So, in the same way that people could
try to craft kind of malicious inputs to
systems. You think about things like SQL
injection as a classic attack of that
kind, where you're injecting something
which you know that on stream will end
up in a SQL query, and someone wasn't
careful, and now you're able to kind of
change the query to be what you want to
do,
away from what the application author
wanted to do.
Um the analog of that, roughly, is
prompt injection in the world of LLMs.
And it's just that instead of being SQL,
it's natural language. And what's
particularly challenging about that is
both the
user input language is natural language
and the programming language of the LLM
is also natural language. And so, when
they come together, it can be hard to
isolate one from the other and ensure
that it's doing what you want,
considering this user input, but not in
the wrong way.
And, you know, what? There's no
fundamental fix for this yet. People are
trying lots of techniques. They're
trying to make it more resistant to
these things, uh by training away some
of it, um and by just doing kind of sort
of heuristic scanning of inputs. Does it
Does this look suspicious, right? Um but
other techniques that we're employing
inside the system, such as decomposing a
problem into smaller parts,
where many of the maybe that user input
only goes to like one of those
subcomponents.
And if you can say confine that
particular input to that subcomponent
and the output of the component is is
something more like structured data,
like what is the likelihood of this
being malicious? Zero to one. Let's just
say as an example.
Then you've effectively confined the
impact of that input to just it can
affect this number and of course you'd
like the number to still be correct, but
at the worst, it'll be the wrong number.
But when you look at the broader
analysis that the system is performing,
it's not going to affect like the
overall plan and the instructions that
are actually getting executed, right?
Which is the kind of thing that in in
general a prompt injection can do.
And so, you know, we're actually looking
at a variety of these kinds of
techniques and it's an area of very
active research.
I love the I love the sort of example
that you gave of using models almost to
help with the to help with the the
defensive testing of hey, you know,
here's an input from a user. Does this
input look malicious or not? And then
and then also decomposing the the higher
level tasks into steps to reduce the
likelihood that if there is something
malicious that it would impact the
entire system as opposed to just a small
part. That's really that's really
interesting and I think it points
towards how people need to completely
rethink how they architect systems in
this in this new world of large language
models.
Very very cool.
So next question. This is this is for
Christopher.
What are the ethical considerations when
creating specialized large language
models for sensitive fields like health
care
and how can you ensure that patient
privacy and data security are maintained
during training um, and also deployment?
Um, so so I, you know, especially if
you're working with things
um,
uh, that might be usually interfaced
with as a REST API as opposed to um,
kind of co-located locally on on site at
a hospital. Um, how are y'all thinking
about that?
Yeah, so for the answers are um, I would
answer training and deployment uh,
separately quickly. So, for deployment
um, there's in many countries local
regulation you can rely on where you're
serving infrastructure simply has to be
compliant with that. So, US for example
has the HIPAA framework and and Google
Cloud infrastructure is is um, compliant
with that. So, that ensures that the
data privacy for the patient data or
other data as well is uh, handled
appropriately during serving time um, as
you might use the data as part of your
prompt and so on.
For training um, there's we usually use
de-identified data or synthetic data.
So, again there's standards per country
on what this precisely means, but you
can see the basics are obviously, you
know, no names, date shifting and stuff
like that.
And that is for two reasons. One is
because it makes a lot of sense from a
patient privacy perspective, uh, but the
second thing is also there's something
about data hygiene like the more
detailed individual data you have in
your training mixture,
the more likely the model might pick up
not only the general patterns, but also
random odd balls that lower your
performance of the model.
So, um, deriving the right level of
abstraction um,
not only with identification, but also
with proper aggregation and so on is
crucial for model performance and also
crucial for making sure that no personal
data leaks into the model itself.
Awesome. That's uh that's great to hear
and I love the call out towards some of
the additional security best practices
that uh that Google Cloud employs for
for making things HIPAA compliant and
making sure that, you know, data's
encrypted in transit and all of that
good stuff. Um excellent.
Um next question, uh also for our
Sicalem team,
um what do you think is the most
effective use of large language models
in solving security problems and why?
What has been some of your favorite use
cases for AI in the security domain?
Uh why don't I start and then Scott can
pick it up as well.
I think Scott really touched on a a key
point earlier, which is
um we see LLMs really unlocking the
ability to perform security tasks
like that procedural knowledge that we
can teach it uh being even more powerful
than kind of the
you know, factual knowledge that the
thing might have.
Because in any case, you can't rely on
the factual knowledge that you think an
LLM has anyway.
Right? You need to ground it in
something authoritative if you want it
that thing to be taken as true, you have
to say it right there in the prompt uh
to have a high confidence.
Right? And you want to make sure that
it's not relying on potentially, you
know, hallucinated information as well.
And so, we take a very strong grounding
approach to anything factual.
And what we really are seeing is that
there's whole workflows where, you know,
we're like, "Okay, what is a person
doing all the time that they would
rather not be doing?"
Right? That we think one of these
systems could do. And maybe actually we
could do 70% of it.
Right? We have kind of
good data sources, we have some
historical examples, we have some code,
you know, regular deterministic code
that can do a lot of it, but there's
some key part that it can't do.
Right? Like, you know, render some
aggregate judgment among multiple
things, figuring out how to use the
tools that we already have available
effectively,
being able to do that iteratively until
you reach a point where you're ready to
make a judgment.
Those kinds of capabilities are pretty
hard to write in regular code.
And so, I I think we're really seeing a
big improvement there.
Um I another one is definitely in the
area of code, you know, code analysis. I
think it's got alluded to for analyzing
potentially malicious things. It's
already proving to be very effective.
And then for code generation, that's
another one of those big missing blocks,
right? So, I would say every year
someone has the idea of, oh, we already
know that people have all these, you
know, potential misconfigurations in
their cloud deployments, like they've
over permissioned some account.
We should just fix it for them.
Okay, but the problem is the actual fix
means you have to generate a pull
request to modify a Terraform file
that's in the customer environment
somewhere.
Right? And that is just not a thing we
were easily able to do because everyone
writes their Terraform a little bit
differently, and it needs to be a
contextual change that has certain
impact.
But with the advent of LLMs, that is
something that we now believe we're
going to be able to do. And so, that's
very transformative even though it's
like in some sense one block
out of the whole thing, it's what makes
that end-to-end thing possible.
Yeah, I was just I I will just add in
like my my view of it is very much that
the LLM is sort of your substrate,
right? It is the thing that's the
connective tissue among all of these
diverse systems that exist inside of
security.
Um because that level of diversity is
exactly what causes all the pain for for
most actual humans, right? The fact that
you have to swivel between that system
and that system or that data silo and
you need to find a way to get it to
merge with that data silo. And it's
exactly what LLMs are great at, right?
Leveraging the APIs and the tools that
are available to them and being able to
combine all this heterogeneous data in a
way that's coherent and reasonable given
enough, you know, prior experience with
exactly what Umesh was saying, right?
This procedural knowledge about what
exactly you should be looking for and
what it means for your final
determination.
And and I I think it's also important to
point out that when when we refer to
customers for Google Cloud, we mean
whole organizations, whole companies.
Um, and so just knowing that the models
are able to flexibly,
you know, change and modify their their
outputs and their recommendations at the
at the company level. Um, uh, is is
really really huge as opposed to having
to have dedicated heuristics and rules
made for each each particular company.
Um, so that's huge. I
This is also a nice tie-in to our next
question, which is what is still one
major gap that you see in large language
model capabilities that make it
that is vital for success in the
security domain, but is a place where
the models just aren't there yet. We've
touched on this a little bit throughout
the duration of the of the chat, but
would love to would love to get your
perspective explicitly.
Yeah, no, this is a really good question
because, you know, for anybody who's
worked in the security domain,
you'll probably come to realize that
most people who work in cybersecurity
are by their very nature incredibly
skeptical about everything.
Right? Like unless there's clear proof
that something has happened, you know,
they're always like, "Ooh, I should go
look into this further, right?" It's
actually been one of the most difficult
points of getting ML, broadly speaking,
into this space is this idea of
explainability and can you trust it and
how do I verify? And I think LLMs just
add a new dimension to this, right? So,
we mentioned this idea of citations or
like grounding, and that's certainly one
way of thinking about it, right? It
certainly goes partway, in my opinion.
The problem is that with grounding, in a
lot of cases, and especially in the way
it's usually used in citations, is
um that that human almost has to do
almost as much work as they probably had
to do to start with to verify all the
things, especially for highly technical
fields, right? So, like, if I'm citing
all of these, you know, threat actor
reports or different reports that are
coming out from Mandiant or other
organizations, then
like
I either have to trust that in fact this
statement that is being cited is there
is there, and it is the implication of
what's in their report, or I need to go
back and just basically read the report
myself, in which case, you know, how
much time am I really saving? So, I
think there's definitely like a a broad
gap here, which is like, how do you
shortcut some of that stuff? How do you
make it so that even in a space where,
you know, it's hard to validate or
verify in some ways, we can minimize
that amount of time to for verification,
or even do things like provide a really
deep, you know, understand like a
confidence score. I know a lot of people
think of like log likelihoods, right?
But that's not really quite it because
that's just your probability of
producing a particular output token
sequence. What I'm saying is like, can
you actually bake in, you know, your
confidence in the underlying grounding
data, your confidence in the reasoning
that you applied, in the same way that a
human analyst would do these sorts of
things? And I think that's the gap where
if we can make that change, that that's
going to unlock
a tremendous amount of value for
customers and users of these systems.
Yeah, I mean Scott gave
a fantastic big picture answer. I'll
give a maybe a slightly smaller picture
answer as well
um in terms of capabilities.
So, um a
again I'm just going to refer to what
Scott said in his previous answer
the ability to stitch together tools,
data sources, APIs
to pull everything that's relevant and
then render judgment is absolutely
critical to solving most security
problems.
And today uh tool use by LLMs is still
fairly rudimentary and takes a lot of
kind of hand tuning to get it to use
those tools effectively.
Right? It's not a case where you can say
here's the API
here's some examples, you know, go use
these things effectively. And that is
particularly acute because in many cases
the API services that we're dealing with
are very wide.
Meaning the schemas that are used to
describe information can have hundreds
or thousands of fields and each one of
them can have some semantic meaning.
And a lot of the stuff that we've seen
in, you know, tool use by LLMs today is
like very I would say very simple or
rudimentary APIs where it's like three
parameters, they're strings, you get
back a sort of simple answer.
Right? And even that has proven
difficult to integrate across APIs in a
way that doesn't require a lot of hand
crafting for each one.
I feel like if we could crack that nut
and
in a scalable way to start handing
tools, pre-existing tools to an LLM and
it could actually understand and use
them
uh that would be that would be game
changing.
Yeah, so that is something that that
folks on this course have been learning
about a little bit earlier in the week
about function calling and tools use and
learning just how uh just how
challenging it can be to get models to
use tools reliably and to know which
tool to use and when.
Um so I I think this is another
inspiration that in addition to better
benchmarks and evals for the medical
domain, um hopefully folks are starting
to think about better evals uh for for
tools use and for function calling as
well, especially for composite tools use
and function calling.
Um excellent. Well, thank you Thank you
both so much. And our final question um
uh for Christopher all about Med-PaLM.
Uh I I saw the Med-PaLM evaluation white
paper on diagnosing depression and PTSD
using client interviews as the basis for
its assessments. How has this work
evolved since then? And it has been I I
I remember when the Med-PaLM paper first
came out. It's been a while. Um
and a while in the large language model
space translates to almost like an
eternity. Um how have things evolved
since Med-PaLM, Chris? Well, yeah, that
paper uh I think was like middle of last
year or so, if I remember correctly. Um
so, for context, the scenario was you
take like a transcript of a
patient-doctor conversation,
and you
given the transcript, what is the likely
diagnosis? And it performed decent. I'm
sure by now it performs much better.
Um but uh
the way I I Again, similar to the answer
with the Med-QA question, it's all about
expanding the scope and moving to a
harder task here.
So, for instance, from a transcript to a
diagnosis, it's not an easy solved task
yet, but it's getting much better than
it was like a year or two ago.
Um but ultimately, what matters for
patients is not really I mean, it's also
to get the correct diagnosis, but what
really matters is that the patient is
going to do the best next thing for the
health. Right? So, that is not only
knowing the right diagnosis and giving
the right recommendation, but also
helping the patient understand so that
they're more likely to do what is best
for them, incorporating the life
situation and everything else.
Um so, we started research along the
lines as well here. That's our research
system AMIE,
um which you can find more about, uh
where we try to evolve um
LLMs not only to take a transcript and
come to conclusion, but also to be the
chat partner in the transcript.
And again, all of this is really early
explorations. Like, even if the model
performs well, there's still the
question of demonstrating it in
real-life environments, in clinical
studies, in a safe way that you can see
how it really makes
a real patient's um effect in a positive
way and so on.
So, we are still in early part of that
journey.
But yeah, it's exciting. Um and I can't
wait to see what's going to happen next.
I love how patient-focused you are about
uh you know, we're using these really
powerful models, but at the end of the
day, the thing that matters most is
whether or not it made uh an impact that
was positive in people's lives. Um so,
on that uh on that really hopeful and
happy note, um I uh thank you all so
much for for coming in for being our
experts um as part of this Q&A. I hope
everybody really loved learning more
about Med-PaLM and about uh Sec-PaLM and
all of the all of the great work that's
been happening in our fine-tuned model
domain at Google um and virtual round of
applause for uh for all of our uh all of
our guests. Um uh with that, uh I think
it's time to go into the next segment of
our
uh of our presentation today, which is
the pop quiz. Um so, we will uh we will
start that just now and and say goodbye
to all of our to all of our great all of
our great guests. Thanks, y'all.
All right, everyone. Hopefully you were
paying attention during our Q&A and when
you were reading the white papers and
walking through the code labs. It is
time for our pop quiz all about
domain-specific large language models,
especially Med-PaLM and Sec-LM. Um, so
number one, what is the primary goal of
Med-LM in the medical field? Is it to
replace doctors with AI systems for more
efficient patient care? Is it to develop
AI models capable of diagnosing and
treating diseases without human
intervention? Is it to improve health
outcomes by making advanced AI
technology available to healthcare
professionals? Or is it to create a
universal AI system that can answer any
medical question with 100% accuracy?
Hopefully everyone was paying attention
during Christopher's answers. And five,
four,
three, two, one.
The answer is C, to improve health
outcomes by making advanced AI
technology available to healthcare
professionals.
It is not designed to
diagnose and treat diseases without
human intervention. It is specifically
designed as a tool to help medical
professionals as they're treating
patients and help patients
with their outcomes. So hopefully
everybody got that answer correct. Next
question, get out your pens and pencils
and paper to get to get ready to write
down your answer. What is the
significance of ensemble refinement,
otherwise known as ER, in Med-PaLM V2?
This was part of one of our white paper,
so hopefully everybody was paying
attention. Is it to allow the model to
learn from patient data? Is it to
improve the model's ability to generate
multiple choice questions? Is it to help
the model identify medical images or is
it to enhance the model's reasoning and
answer refinement by conditioning it on
multiple generated reason pathways? Um
five
four
three
two
one
The answer is D. It enhances the model's
reasoning and answer refinement by
conditioning it on multiple generated
reason pathways. Hopefully, everybody
got this answer correct and if you did
not, refer back to the white paper
specifically focused on Med-PaLM.
Question number three. What is the
innovative approach used by Sec-PaLM to
address security challenges? Um is it A
to develop a highly complex AI model
with trillions of parameters for
superior performance? Is it B to replace
human security analysts with fully
autonomous AI agents? Is it C to combine
large language models, authoritative
data sources, and a flexible planning
framework? Or is it D to create a global
database of all known cyber threats for
real-time threat detection? Um what is
the innovative approach used by Sec-PaLM
um that you heard about from Umash and
Scott? Um and everybody jot down their
answer.
I'm going to show the answer in five
four
three
two
one The answer is C to combine large
language models, authoritative data
sources, and a flexible planning
framework to get the best results for
security use cases.
Question number four. How does Sec-PaLM
address the challenge of limited
publicly available security data? Um is
it A by collecting and storing sensitive
user data for central model training? Is
it by B developing specialized LLMs
trained on cybersecurity specific
content and tasks? Is it C by relying
solely on open-source security data for
model training? Or D by generating
synthetic security data to augment
limited public data? I'm going to show
the answer in five four
three
two 1. The answer is B. It develops
specialized LLMs trained on
cybersecurity specific content and
tasks. It does not train on user data,
and it does not generate synthetic data
to augment public data. It just trains
on the specific kinds of use cases
that folks in the the cybersecurity
domain might be interested in. And with
that, I hope everybody really enjoyed
this section. I certainly did
specifically focused on medical and
security domain specific large language
models.
Hopefully you learned a lot, and I am
really really excited
about tomorrow being our fifth and final
day for the generative AI intensive
course on Kaggle.
You know, we've learned this week all
about prompting,
about using large language models to
solve specific tasks, about function
calling, and retrieval, and about using
vector databases to help ground ground
models outputs. Today we learned about
fine-tuning and about domain specific
models, and tomorrow we're going to
learn all about evals and about ML ops
for the generative model space.
So really excited and hope to see you
there.
Make sure to do your podcast listens,
your white paper reads, and ask all of
your questions on Discord, and you might
get your question featured in one of our
videos. Thank you so much, and have a
great rest of your day.